<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>l0.ai</title>
    <link>https://l0.ai/</link>
    <description>Recent content on l0.ai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://l0.ai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neurips 2023, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-12-20-neurips-2023-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-12-20-neurips-2023-1/</guid>
      <description>Neurips 2023 Wrap-up - Posters (main conference) Neurips 2023, held in New Orleans once again, just finished. The last part of the Neurips ritual for me, is to pool my notes and write a wrap-up (or more than one), where I can reflect over what I saw in the conference that stood out or I want to pay attention to.
In a very real way, over the past few years, Neurips has set the agenda for what I pay attention to in the field of machine learning over the following year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty weighted impact</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-09-03-uncertainty_weighted_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-09-03-uncertainty_weighted_impact/</guid>
      <description>The joys of the start-up journey have been neatly summarised a number of times. Some choice examples are &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like building a plane while it plummets back to earth&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like staring into the abyss and eating glass&amp;rdquo;
Part of that struggle is to understand what to build next, before customers are ripping product out of your hands (also known as product market fit). There is only 1 answer: talk to customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common challenges as a new EM</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-08-01-common_challenges_as_a_new_em/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-08-01-common_challenges_as_a_new_em/</guid>
      <description>It was about 8pm, I was at bar with friends, not yet done with my first pint. 2 separate clients reached out about their EPGs not working. One of them, ITV, let us know the little rectangle on their website that told folks what was on TV was blank. It seems quaint today, now that most everything is on demand.
I opened an app on my phone to attempt to view logs and manage our servers - almost enjoying the interruption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The duality of knowledge and control</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-07-01-knowledge-and-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-07-01-knowledge-and-control/</guid>
      <description>In experimentation, you leverage control to gain knowledge, in engineering you leverage knowledge to gain control.
I recently used this paraphrasing of a quote from Claude Shannon during a conversation with a team considering changes to experimentation tooling. This framing forces you to clarify what you mean to do - something generally useful.
A more general take on this quote replaces engineering with delivery. That is, in delivery you should be leveraging what you know to effect a change in a system, for instance a new entry point in a product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selecting high potential individuals and the moral quandry N. 2</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-06-06-hipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-06-06-hipo/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post post I shared some reflections about how I apportion time given a set of reports - and highlighted my use of the potential (especially appetite) and efficacy of that time given the report, to answer the question: who should I give more time to?
That post aimed to address how to think through time allocation, but didn&amp;rsquo;t speak to high potential individuals and the work of finding and nurturing them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlivery cadence and capacity, a team&#39;s delivery does not grow linearly with size</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-11-devlivery-cadence-and-capacity-a-teams-delivery-does-not-grow-linearly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-11-devlivery-cadence-and-capacity-a-teams-delivery-does-not-grow-linearly/</guid>
      <description>A significant part of my job in the past has been to plan for the growth of an engineering organization. There are a number of things to consider when doing this:
Why do you need the growth? Really though, specifically what value do you intend to create with the growth? This first concern should be clear, but being comprehensive pays dividends later.
Why are you growing?
What business value do you intend to deliver with that growth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selecting high potential individuals and the moral quandry N. 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-04-with-limited-time-who-do-you-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-04-with-limited-time-who-do-you-support/</guid>
      <description>Through out your career as an engineering manager you&amp;rsquo;ll be faced with the challenge of supporting individuals with different development potential. With finite time this will force a difficult question: where to focus your efforts?. Like most difficult questions, this one has a moral quality to it.
A potentially naive answer is to put an equal amount of time into developing each person: it feels like the fair thing to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlivery Metrics</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-03-delivery-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-02-03-delivery-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Delivery Metrics Delivery metrics are critical to understanding your teams&amp;rsquo; performance - but, this truth stems from something much deeper and important: value. Delivery metrics are a model teams use to undertstand the delivery of value, often before that value materialises into a terminal outcome (quite often financial).
The common stats aphorism &amp;ldquo;All models are wrong, but some are useful&amp;rdquo; holds true for delivery metrics too - so more than just finding the right metric, as an engineering manager, you are looking to create an environment where squads seek to continuosly improve their understanding of value delivery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio of Work</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-01-12-portfolio-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-01-12-portfolio-of-work/</guid>
      <description>Portfolio of work Many spinning plates is something I have often heard in the context of work (including mine) - I&amp;rsquo;ve used it! I find this is a poor analogy, and if indeed it is apt as an analogy, then there is an issue: fragility. I picture a brittle juggling act to keep all those plates spinning, rushing from one to the next, always under stress.
I rather think of managing a portfolio of work, where the return profile of that work varies, most usefully, along two key axes: timeline to impact and likelihood of impact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neurips Wrapup Post 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-12-10-neurips-2022-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-12-10-neurips-2022-1/</guid>
      <description>Neurips 2022 - A wrap up post #1 Neurips 2022 has just finished - and it was a great conference! It was my first proper conference since Covid, and it was so much fun. I don&amp;rsquo;t go to Neurips to present, but rather to absorb. Over time, it has become part of my yearly calendar that I really look forward to. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to reconnect with what is happening at the edge of deep learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Stable Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-9-fast-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-9-fast-diffusion/</guid>
      <description>Fast Stable Diffusion I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with Stable Diffusion recently - from just playing with prompt, to trying out Textual Inversion and Dreambooth.
I&amp;rsquo;ve opted not to use services or Web GUI&amp;rsquo;s - not because I dislike them, but rather because I was looking to learn about diffusion models and the infrastructure to use them, and get amazing pictures as a side effect. Stable diffusion has this great property : it can fit in a lot of consumer grade hardware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Experiment 3</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</guid>
      <description>Imagining myself in new images Textual Inversion In an earlier post I referenced work on Textual Inversion that allows new concepts to be added to the Stable Diffusion model. Textual inversion trains a new set of embeddings that can be used to generate a new object or style you provide through pictures, by loading them into a model. I used textual inversion to generate some portraits of our pup, though this worked well and generated some beautiful images it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly like our dog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pyramid Principle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</guid>
      <description>I left the meeting and I felt terrible - I knew I could do better
I had just walked out of the room from a meeting with the folks that ran community integrity at Facebook. I had really boched an answer that was likely to make my life harder later. As I left the room, a very senior engineer, who is a legend at the company, took me to one side and said quite plainly: just answer the question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rhetorical triangle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</guid>
      <description>The rhetorical triangle Last Friday, I found myself using the framing of the rhetorical triangle again, in the context of an engineering management discussion. I thought I should put pen to paper given how much I use it.
The rhetorical triangle is composed of three corners: ethos, pathos, logos. It is used in rhetrocial analysis and as a means of taking a rhetorical stance - one that is suitable for the audience and the context - in both oratory and writing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 2-4</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 2 Sketch 3 Sketch 4 As I continue to explore Stable Diffusion, I&amp;rsquo;m more and more impressed by a few things: some grasp of compositionality, wide breadth of concepts or semantics in the model and very impressive quality in its generations. The images below weren&amp;rsquo;t hand picked, I&amp;rsquo;ve put other generations here too.
Sketch 2 Prompt: : &amp;ldquo;Low poly art of a floating island sourrounded by waterfalls with a japanese temple built with red wood, isometric art, 3d render, ray tracing, high detail, artstation, concept art, behance, smooth, sharp focus, ethereal lighting, unreal engine 5&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 1 Prompt: &amp;ldquo;Pixar Style, puppy schnauzer adventurer, blue eye, tiny cute adorable, villain, unreal engine, dramatic lighting, 8k, portrait, 50mm&amp;rdquo;
generated image of Miniture Shcnauzer cartoon Stable Diffusion is pretty incredible. It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-modal generative model, most easily used through hugging face, that you do not need to pay for, unlike DALLE-2 or Midjourney.
It is fascinating, and really highlights a question that now feels a little old and yet somehow super relevant: will there be a labour market for prompt engineers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A neuro-symbolic ARC parser</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-19-a-neuro-symbolic-arc-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 09:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-19-a-neuro-symbolic-arc-parser/</guid>
      <description>Intro This previous post introduces why I think the abstraction and reasoning corpus (ARC) from this paper is a worthy challenge to pursue for robust ML research. As a quick explainer, the ARC dataset is composed of tasks like this one: An ARC Task. The top row are the starting prompts, the bottom row are the correct answers. In this task you can produce the correct answer by: finding objects with the same shape as the object contained by the top left grey border and recoloring those objects to grey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is not the full video</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-11-this-is-not-the-whole-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-11-this-is-not-the-whole-video/</guid>
      <description>This is not the full video TL;DR: video recording devices or apps that follow ‘a standard’, sign each frame of a video being recorded with the last frame’s signature. Video hosting platforms or news outlets can compute if they have the last frame (and wether the video has been tampered) - and surface this information to users using merkle trees
A half baked idea As an increasing amount of user generated video on platforms like Youtube, Twitter and Facebook cover current events - and become part of the ‘news’ - a significant (though certainly not new) problem arises for the viewer: can I trust this content?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why ARC?</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-arc-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 15:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-arc-intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro In November 2019, François Chollet released a paper called &amp;ldquo;On the measure of Intelligence&amp;rdquo;. I highly recommend you read this paper if you have interest in AGI. You can very roughly split the work into two, lopsided pieces: the paper and the abstraction and reasoning corpus (ARC) dataset.
There are plenty of great discussions of the paper, among them this post and a series of videos, which I suggest you read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trilemma communication device</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 14:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</guid>
      <description>The trilemma communication device The trilemma, a choice where you have to pick 2 out of 3 properties, appears often - and more than an intrinsic characteristic of social or productive systems, it&amp;rsquo;s a useful communication device. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s a more nuanced trade-off representation than the dichotomy.
Dichotomy as a comms device is common: do you want to be &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo;. Dichotomies are often either false in contradiction or false in antinomy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Guillermo. I work in technology.
Usually building teams or technology that explores the space between machine intelligence and product experience. I&amp;rsquo;ve done this at a very large social media company, at a number of start-ups (including my own!) and larger co&amp;rsquo;s.
l0.ai is where I write. Most often about technology: machine learning, engineering management and communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Page</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/test/</guid>
      <description> Token: Upload files: </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
