<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>comms on l0.ai</title>
    <link>https://l0.ai/tags/comms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in comms on l0.ai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://l0.ai/tags/comms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio of Work</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-01-12-portfolio-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2023-01-12-portfolio-of-work/</guid>
      <description>Portfolio of work Many spinning plates is something I have often heard in the context of work (including mine) - I&amp;rsquo;ve used it! I find this is a poor analogy, and if indeed it is apt as an analogy, then there is an issue: fragility. I picture a brittle juggling act to keep all those plates spinning, rushing from one to the next, always under stress.
I rather think of managing a portfolio of work, where the return profile of that work varies, most usefully, along two key axes: timeline to impact and likelihood of impact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pyramid Principle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</guid>
      <description>I left the meeting and I felt terrible - I knew I could do better
I had just walked out of the room from a meeting with the folks that ran community integrity at Facebook. I had really boched an answer that was likely to make my life harder later. As I left the room, a very senior engineer, who is a legend at the company, took me to one side and said quite plainly: just answer the question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rhetorical triangle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</guid>
      <description>The rhetorical triangle Last Friday, I found myself using the framing of the rhetorical triangle again, in the context of an engineering management discussion. I thought I should put pen to paper given how much I use it.
The rhetorical triangle is composed of three corners: ethos, pathos, logos. It is used in rhetrocial analysis and as a means of taking a rhetorical stance - one that is suitable for the audience and the context - in both oratory and writing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trilemma communication device</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 14:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</guid>
      <description>The trilemma communication device The trilemma, a choice where you have to pick 2 out of 3 properties, appears often - and more than an intrinsic characteristic of social or productive systems, it&amp;rsquo;s a useful communication device. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s a more nuanced trade-off representation than the dichotomy.
Dichotomy as a comms device is common: do you want to be &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo;. Dichotomies are often either false in contradiction or false in antinomy.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
