<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>art on l0.ai</title>
    <link>https://l0.ai/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art on l0.ai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:25:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://l0.ai/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Experiment 3</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</guid>
      <description>Imagining myself in new images Textual Inversion In an earlier post I referenced work on Textual Inversion that allows new concepts to be added to the Stable Diffusion model. Textual inversion trains a new set of embeddings that can be used to generate a new object or style you provide through pictures, by loading them into a model.       I used textual inversion to generate some portraits of our pup, though this worked well and generated some beautiful images it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly like our dog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 2-4</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 2 Sketch 3 Sketch 4   As I continue to explore Stable Diffusion, I&amp;rsquo;m more and more impressed by a few things: some grasp of compositionality, wide breadth of concepts or semantics in the model and very impressive quality in it&amp;rsquo;s generations. The images below weren&amp;rsquo;t hand picked, I&amp;rsquo;ve put other generations here too.
Sketch 2 Prompt: : &amp;ldquo;Low poly art of a floating island sourrounded by waterfalls with a japanese temple built with red wood, isometric art, 3d render, ray tracing, high detail, artstation, concept art, behance, smooth, sharp focus, ethereal lighting, unreal engine 5&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 1 Prompt: &amp;ldquo;Pixar Style, puppy schnauzer adventurer, blue eye, tiny cute adorable, villain, unreal engine, dramatic lighting, 8k, portrait, 50mm&amp;rdquo;
  generated image of Miniture Shcnauzer cartoon   Stable Diffusion is pretty incredible. It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-modal generative model, most easily used through hugging face, that you do not need to pay for, unlike DALLE-2 or Midjourney.
It is fascinating, and really highlights a questions that now feels a little old and yet somehow super relevant: will there be a labour market for prompt engineers?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>