<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on l0.ai</title>
    <link>https://l0.ai/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on l0.ai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:25:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://l0.ai/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Experiment 3</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-6-stable-diffusion-3/</guid>
      <description>Imagining myself in new images Textual Inversion In an earlier post I referenced work on Textual Inversion that allows new concepts to be added to the Stable Diffusion model. Textual inversion trains a new set of embeddings that can be used to generate a new object or style you provide through pictures.       I used textual inversion to generate some portraits of our pup, though this worked well and generated some beautiful images it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly like our dog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pyramid Principle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-11-04-the-pyramid-principle/</guid>
      <description>I left the meeting and I felt terrible - I knew I could do better
I had just walked out of the room from a meeting with the folks that ran community integrity at Facebook. I had really boched an answer that was likely to make my life harder later. As I left the room, a very senior engineer, who is a legend at the company, took me to one side and said quite plainly: just answer the question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rhetorical triangle</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-10-29-rhetorical-triangle/</guid>
      <description>The rhetorical triangle Last Friday, I found myself using the framing of the rhetorical triangle again, in the context of an engineering management discussion. I thought I should put pen to paper given how much I use it.
The rhetorical triangle is composed of three corners: ethos, pathos, logos. It is used in rhetrocial analysis and as a means of taking a rhetorical stance - one that is suitable for the audience and the context - in both oratory and writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 2-4</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-17-stable-diffusion-sketch2/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 2 Sketch 3 Sketch 4   As I continue to explore Stable Diffusion, I&amp;rsquo;m more and more impressed by a few things: some grasp of compositionality, wide breadth of concepts or semantics in the model and very impressive quality in it&amp;rsquo;s generations. The images below weren&amp;rsquo;t hand picked, I&amp;rsquo;ve put other generations here too.
Sketch 2 Prompt: : &amp;ldquo;Low poly art of a floating island sourrounded by waterfalls with a japanese temple built with red wood, isometric art, 3d render, ray tracing, high detail, artstation, concept art, behance, smooth, sharp focus, ethereal lighting, unreal engine 5&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion Sketch 1</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 16:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2022-09-11-stable-diffusion-sketch1/</guid>
      <description>Sketch 1 Prompt: &amp;ldquo;Pixar Style, puppy schnauzer adventurer, blue eye, tiny cute adorable, villain, unreal engine, dramatic lighting, 8k, portrait, 50mm&amp;rdquo;
  generated image of Miniture Shcnauzer cartoon   Stable Diffusion is pretty incredible. It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-modal generative model, most easily used through hugging face, that you do not need to pay for, unlike DALLE-2 or Midjourney.
It is fascinating, and really highlights a questions that now feels a little old and yet somehow super relevant: will there be a labour market for prompt engineers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A neuro-symbolic ARC parser</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-19-a-neuro-symbolic-arc-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 09:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-19-a-neuro-symbolic-arc-parser/</guid>
      <description>Intro This previous post introduces why I think the abstraction and reasoning corpus (ARC) from this paper is a worthy challenge to pursue for robust ML research. As a quick explainer, the ARC dataset is composed of tasks like this one:   An ARC Task. The top row are the starting prompts, the bottom row are the correct answers.   In this task you can produce the correct answer by: finding objects with the same shape as the object contained by the top left grey border and recoloring those objects to grey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is not the full video</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-11-this-is-not-the-whole-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2021-01-11-this-is-not-the-whole-video/</guid>
      <description>This is not the full video TL;DR: video recording devices or apps that follow ‘a standard’, sign each frame of a video being recorded with the last frame’s signature. Video hosting platforms or news outlets can compute if they have the last frame (and wether the video has been tampered) - and surface this information to users using merkle trees
A half baked idea As an increasing amount of user generated video on platforms like Youtube, Twitter and Facebook cover current events - and become part of the ‘news’ - a significant (though certainly not new) problem arises for the viewer: can I trust this content?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ARC?</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-arc-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 15:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-arc-intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro In November 2019, François Chollet released a paper called &amp;ldquo;On the measure of Intelligence&amp;rdquo;. I highly recommend you read this paper if you have interest in AGI. You can very roughly split the work into two, lopsided pieces: the paper and the abstraction and reasoning corpus (ARC) dataset.
There are plenty of great discussions of the paper, among them this post and a series of videos, which I suggest you read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trilemma communication device</title>
      <link>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 14:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://l0.ai/posts/2020-12-22-trilema-device/</guid>
      <description>The trilemma communication device The trilemma, a choice where you have to pick 2 out of 3 properties, appears often - and more than an intrinsic characteristic of social or productive systems, it&amp;rsquo;s a useful communication device. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s a more nuanced trade-off representation than the dichotomy.
Dichotomy as a comms device is common: do you want to be &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo;. Dichotomies are often either false in contradiction or false in antinomy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>